

## Mazhar Ahmed

+880 1712 999908 info@mazharAhmed.me Mohammadpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh

### **Profile**

I am Mazhar Ahmed, a Zend Certified Engineer. I am a web technology expert with more than 9 years of experience. I am full-stack **LAMP** (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP), **Python** (Mostly Django) and **MEAN** (MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, NodeJS) architect. I am also a Payment Gateway Expert.

My career objective is to build killer web services that people will love to use, and also making the payment gateways transparent, secured and more convenient.

# Experience

**1. INTERCONNECTION LTD.; DHAKA, BANGLADESH – FEB, 2017 – PRESENT** as Senior Software Architect. Worked with Python, Django, PostgreSQL etc.

### PRODUCTS:

#### GUITAR MOTEL

A platform for the guitar lovers. Built on top of Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, JWT, HTML, CSS, Javascript, ElasticSearch, Redis, AngularJS, PostgreSQL <a href="https://www.guitarmotel.com">www.guitarmotel.com</a>

2. KONA SOFTWARE LAB LTD.; DHAKA, BANGLADESH – APR, 2016 – JAN, 2017 as Lead Engineer. Worked with PHP, JavaEE, Javascript, HTML, Oracle, MySQL.

### PRODUCTS:

#### KONA MONEY

A uniformed payment platform / solution. It supports HCE, OTP, CardSE, NFC Payment, POS Payments. It's available on iOS & Android for end users. Built on top of JavaEE, Spring Framework, Oracle 11g, Android, Objective-C. www.konamoney.com

#### KONA ERP

A ERP for Kona Software Lab Ltd. Built on top of Symfony Framework, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript.

3. ST SOLUTIONS INTERNATIONAL LLC; DHAKA, BANGLADESH – DEC, 2009 – APR, 2016 as CTO. Worked with PHP, Python, Ruby, HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Neo4j, ElasticSearch, Apache Solr.

#### PRODUCTS:

#### MADEFRESHLY

A hosted e-commerce solution for entrepreneurs. It is built on top of PHP, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL, Varnish Cache, AWS, C++, Memcached, MongoDB www.madefreshly.com

### JOONOMY

A social job search platform for the professionals. It is built on top of PHP, MySQL, Neo4j, Apache Solr, HTML, CSS, Javascript, AWS, Redis. <a href="https://www.joonomy.com">www.joonomy.com</a>

#### MEGHDOOT

A online tourism site for travelers in Bangladesh. Built on top of PHP, MySQL, ElasticSearch, Redis, AWS, HTML, CSS, Javascript. <a href="https://www.meghdoot.com">www.meghdoot.com</a>

#### PROJECT COOL

A project management tool which supports realtime chat. Built on top of Ruby-on-Rails, HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL.

#### KNIT CHART

A knitting chart management tool for the garments managers. Built on top of Python, Django, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Javascript.

### 4. C+S COMPUTER SYSTEM; DHAKA, BANGLADESH - MAR, 2008 - DEC, 2009

as C# Programmer and Trainer. Worked on a product named "Blood Donation Management System" which is being used by schools and colleges.

# Education

National University of Bangladesh – **M.Sc. in Computer Science**, 2010 National University of Bangladesh – B.Sc. (Hons.) in Computer Science, 2008 Cantonment College, Jessore – H.S.C. in Science, 2004 Khash Mathurapur High School, Jessore – S.S.C. in Science, 2002

## Skills

Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, Flask, JWT, Redis, AngularJS, Gulp, ElasticSearch, Docker, PHP, Symfony, Codelgniter, Laravel, CakePHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, SailsJS, Amazon AWS, Linux, Nginx, Apache HTTP Server, JavaEE, JavaSE, Spring Framework, Apache Solr, CouchDB, Neo4j

## References

#### **Steve Wong**

Founder & CEO, Joonomy stevewong 22@gmail.com

### **Trin Salaloy**

Founder & CEO, MadeFreshly trinsalaloy@gmail.com